# Tausif Solaiman

<u>Tausifsolaiman@gmail.com</u> | New York, NY | Mobile: (631) 568 7873 https://github.com/TauSolaiman | www.linkedin.com/in/tausif-solaiman

# **EDUCATION**

# **CUNY Baruch College, Zicklin School of Business**

Expected June 2021

B.B.A in Information Systems | GPA: 3.1

# **Fullstack Academy**

Web Development Fellowship

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

# SUMMARY

I am a senior with an interest in Web Development and Data Analytics with a goal of pursuing a MS in Data Analytics post-graduation. I have worked extensively with web development tools & frameworks at Fullstack Academy and I enjoy working with new innovative technologies and challenging myself.

#### PROJECTS

Squeezy

Developer / https://sqlmadeeasy.onrender.com/chat / https://github.com/SQLMadeEasy

- Collaborated in a team of three to create an English to SQL query chatbot that allows the user to make SQL queries though chatbot interaction.
- Built Frontend UI using React and Redux, architected API request structure, and styled using Reactstrap
- Tech Stack: Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Sequelize, Recharts, and styled with Reactstrap

# Trade Strategies in Python

Sole Developer / https://github.com/TauSolaiman/Trade-Strategies-Python

- Algorithmic trading strategies using python, created for Binance Exchange.
- Generates trading models displaying buy and sell signals for currently traded assets on Binance, and backtests data to determine the effectiveness of trade strategies such as moving average and Bollinger Bands strategy
- Tools: pyti, plotly, and pandas

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineering Student, Fullstack Academy

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

17-week immersive software engineering program with a focus on full stack web development.
Developed knowledge in computer science principles including data structures and algorithms, frontend development, back-end development, databases, tools and best practices, simulating the real-world software development process.

### Tax Intern. Icon Information Consultants

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

- Reconcile Schedule K-1 forms for newly acquired clients for the years 2008 2017
- Organize and track personal income tax returns for clients of U.S trust

### Client Services Intern, Tax Technologies, Inc.

Jan 2019 - June 2019

- Implement engagements for new clients, including performing data conversion, integration, and set up in Tax Technologies' proprietary software
- Analyze 15+ reports on a weekly basis to validate data flow through Tax software
- Research Country by Country reporting compliance using Wolters Kluwer IntelliConnect database for essential Tax applications

# SKILLS & LANGUAGE

- Programming Languages, Tools and Frameworks: Python, JavaScript, Node, Express, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, JSON, AJAX, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Git, Plotly, Pandas
- Languages: Fluency in Bangla, Intermediate in Spanish